Guide to the Leigh N. Ortenburger Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 3: Teton Climber's Guide
  - Subseries 3.1: Notes, typescripts, page proofs, illustrations, and correspondence
    - Reed, John C., Jr., geologic map of Tetons (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Tetons, geology (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Grand Teton National Park, copies of articles (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Jackson Hole newspapers, early clippings (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Moran, Thomas, "The Great Teton Range, Idaho," illustration from Harpers Weekly, 12/9/1882 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Tetons, miscellaneous map copies (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Tetons, map tracings (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Tetons, maps conjoined (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Allan, Esther B., "History of the Teton National Forest," photocopy of typescript (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Fryxell, Fritiof M., bibliography on index cards re Tetons (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Ortenburger, Leigh N., "A Climber's Guide to the Teton Range," early draft with comments, 1956 edition (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - More comments by Fryxell, Fritiof M. (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
    - Ortenburger, Leigh N., "A Climber's Guide to the Teton Range," final draft, 1956 edition, (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Ortenburger, Leigh N., "A Climber's Guide to the Teton Range," final draft, 1956 edition, (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Ortenburger, Leigh N., page proof of 1956 guidebook, some pages missing (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Ortenburger, Leigh N., "A Climber's Guide to the Teton Range," final draft, 1965 edition (Box 7, Folder 2-5)
    - Ortenburger, Leigh N., "A Climber's Guide to the Teton Range," condensed, 1979 edition, proof copies (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Ortenburger, Leigh N. and Jackson, Reynold G., "A Climber's Guide to the Teton Range," Volume II, condensed, draft, 1987 edition (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Volume II, condensed, final text, 1987 edition (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
    - Volume II, condensed, topos, 1987 edition (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Volume II, condensed, page proofs, 1987 edition (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Volume II, pasteup, 1987 edition (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Volume II, page proofs, 1987 edition (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
    - Ortenburger, Leigh N., "Complete List of Teton Routes," typescript, 1990 edition (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Ortenburger, Leigh N. and Jackson, Reynold G., "A Complete Guide to the Teton Range," Volumes I and II, 1990 edition, page proofs (Box 10, Folder 2-6)
    - Guidebook correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Guidebook correspondence, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Reed, John C., Jr., geology section typescript, 1956 edition (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Dye, Eldon N., correspondence re drawings for 1956 edition (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Grand Teton National Park, miscellaneous correspondence re trails, 1936, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Articles re Tetons, 1926, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Bibliography for 1956, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Guidebook correspondence, 1957-1963 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Guidebook correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence re Climber's Campground, 1959-1961, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Route time information analysis through 1963 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Articles re classification of difficulty, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Classification, miscellaneous notes (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Classification correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 11, Folder 14-16)
    - Classification of routes, summary, no date (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Exum Mountain Guide Service, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Articles re Tetons, 1950-1963 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Guidebook miscellaneous notes, 1960s-1970s (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Articles re Tetons, 1967-1986 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Route time information data through 1973 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Sierra Club (guidebook publisher), correspondence 1961-1967 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Guidebook correspondence, 1966-1978 (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
    - Sierra Club (guidebook publisher), correspondence 1972-1975 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Grand Teton National Park handouts, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Weissner, Fritz H., classification correspondence, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Smutek, Ray, classification correspondence, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Rescue from North Face of Grand Teton, Humphrey, Hubert H., Udall, Stewart, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Annual climb lists, 1957-1977 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Ascents of the Grand Teton, 1898-1974 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Teton miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Teton Guide Book Business Records 1973-1990 (Box 13, Folder 1-12)
    - Weather at Moose, Wyoming, 1975-1988 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Climate of Yellowstone and Grand Teton 1774-77, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - National Park Service Policy, draft, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Weather, notes and draft, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Guidebook notes, 1970s-1980s (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Guidebook notes, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Guidebook correspondence, 1980-1988 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Computer usage, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Index to outgoing correspondence, winter 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Suggested mountain patrols, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - National Park Service Policy, park information, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - National Park Service Policy, correspondence, Armington, Peter and Nelson, Doyle, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - National Park Service Policy, guiding, backcountry, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Thuermer, Angus M., notes on routes, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Harrington, Randall P., correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Helicopter flights, 1988(?) (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Annual climb lists, 1976-1991 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Reed, John C., Jr., geology chapter 1988 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Weather, Idaho and Wyoming (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Probability of lightning strike, 1975-1988 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Statistics of early climbs (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Topographic quads of Tetons, provisional, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Teton maps, miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Composite United States Geological Survey maps of Tetons (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Copyright for "A Climber's Guide..." Vol. II (condensed) (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - A Complete Climber's Guide... geology, maps, peaks, lists (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Articles re winter climbing, Stagner, Howard R.; Lowe, Jeff; Wilcox, Rick; Turville, Dennis; 1935-1991 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Notes and correspondence re winter climbing, 1963-1991 (Box 15, Folder 6-8)
    - First winter ascents, drafts, 1990 edition (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Winter climbing chapter, drafts, 1990 edition (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Topo art, 1990 edition (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Maps and cover art, 1990 edition (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Cover and title page, 1990 edition (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Printing and binding, 1990 edition (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Teton newspaper clippings, 1987-1991 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Trails information 1990-1991 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Maps, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Guidebook photos, preliminary list (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Typescripts, Death Canyon to Garnet Canyon (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Typescripts, Teewinot and Mount Owen (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Typescripts, Grand Teton (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Typescripts, Storm Point to Mount Woodring (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Typescripts, Leigh Canyon to Waterfalls Canyon (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Typescripts, miscellaneous, no date, no captions (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Printing information (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Various drafts for 1990 edition (Box 16, Folder 12-13)
    - Jackson, Reynold G., correspondence re editing, 1992-1993 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Section 4, unknown date, (edited by Ortenburger, Leigh N.?) (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Section 1, draft, 1990s (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Section 4, draft, with editing, 1990s (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Section 6, draft (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Section 7, draft (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Subseries 3.2: Dye, Eldon N., original drawings for 1956 edition of guidebook, and all subsequent editions
    - Thor Peak from East (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Okie's Thumb (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Veiled Peak (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Storm Point (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Grand Teton from south (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Teepe Pillar (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Cloudveil Dome (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Molar Tooth (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Nez Perce to South Teton (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Teepe Pillar (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Shadow Peak (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Ice Point (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Ridge above Lake of the Crags (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Middle Teton (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Nez Perce (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Buck Mountain (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Mount Moran (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Nez Perce (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Teewinot and Mount Owen (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Buck Mountain (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Stanford Pinnacle (Baxter's Lost Pinnacle) (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Stanford Pinnacle (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Mount Owen (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Buck Mountain and Static Peak (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Ridge between Disappointment Peak and Grand Teton (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Mount Moran (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Grand Teton from southeast (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Teewinot (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Thor Peak, Mount Owen (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Grand Teton, Symmetry Spire (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Teepe Pillar, North Face of Disappointment Peak (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Dye, Eldon N., oversize original drawing of Disappointment Peak from the south (Box 76, Folder 1)
- Series 4: Grand Teton National Park (GTNP) Plans and Development
  This series contains park planning documents, newspaper articles, and correspondence about historic preservation and other issues in GTNP. Correspondents include: Brady, James M.; Bricher-Wade, Sheila; Brink, Peter; Carter, Thomas; Cranston, Alan; D'Ascenz, Jo Ann; Danz, Harold P.; Deland, Michael; Drury, Newton B.; Duffy, Katy; Fink, Robert; Forbes, Timothy C.; Galvin, Dennis; Gardner, A. Dudley; Garland, R. Scott; Gingery, Marshall A.; Hartzog, Jr., George B.; Iliff, Bernard; Kathka, David; Kostmayer, Peter; Lamb, George R.; Levy, Ben; Marceau, Thomas E.; Massey, Rheba; McCain, Jr., Art; McWilliams, Carl; Mehls, Carol; Mehls, Steven F.; Mendiola, Steven L.; Mintzmyer, Lorraine; Neckels, Jack; Nissley, Claudia; Ortenburger, Leigh N.; Powell, Jackie W.; Resor, Bill; Rockefeller, Laurance S.; Rouse, Homer L.; Shrook, Betty; Simpson, Alan K.; Stark, Jack E.; Storey, Brit; Strait, Richard A.; Strickland, Clark J.; Toogood, A. C.; Unsoeld, Jolene; Wheaton, Rodd L.; Wilson, Pete, et al.
  - GTNP, airport expansion, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - GTNP, articles (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - GTNP, floodplain management, 1977-1984 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Historic Preservation, government publications (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - GTNP, National Register of Historic Places, 1986-1988 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - GTNP, Classified Structure Field Inventory Reports, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Project to remove X Quarter Circle X Ranch, 1/26/1989 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Historic preservation correspondence, 1968, 1985-1991 (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
  - Historic preservation workshop, comments, 6/14/1990 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Wyoming State Historical Preservation Office (WYSHPO), Surveys (Box 17, Folder 11-13)
  - WYSHPO publications, 1985-1989 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Reconstruction of Teton Park Road and Jenny Lake Road, environmental assessment, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - GTNP Statement for Management, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - GTNP East Corridor Management Plan, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - GTNP newspaper clippings, 1900-1991 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Teton Corridor Development Concept Plan (DCP), Environmental Assessment, draft, 4/1/1990 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Teton Corridor DCP, comments by Ortenburger, Leigh N., 9/6/1990 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Teton Corridor DCP, final version 2/12/1991 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Teton Corridor DCP, correspondence 1945, 1986, 1988-1991 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - GTNP road realignment and Jenny Lake plan, notes, 1988-1990 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - GTNP road realignment and Jenny Lake plan, government documents (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Teton Corridor DCP, Death Canyon trailhead, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - GTNP Jenny Lake, correspondence, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - GTNP, maps (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - GTNP road realignment, correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Ortenburger, Leigh N., letter to Garland, R. Scott, Jackson Hole Alliance, re park planning and historic preservation, 11/9/1991 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Inyo National Forest, Land and Resource Management Plan (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - National Park Service (NPS) Planning Process, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - NPS Environmental Policy Act Guideline, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - NPS Management Policies, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - NPS Winter Use Plan, 1990, Vision for Future, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Briceland, Richard, "Public Perceptions about the National Parks, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Series 5: Family and Personal
  This series contains information on the family, education, and interests of Ortenburger, Leigh N., and correspondence, including: Datena, John F.; Deam, Calvin; Deam, Stella (Mrs. Charles C. Deam); Deam, Charles C.; Deam, Roberta E.; Merriam, C. Hart; Ortenburger, Thomas; Ortenburger, Arthur I., Jr.; Ortenburger, Robert D.; Ortenburger, Mark; Ortenburger, Teresa A.; Park, Fred, et al.
  - Deam family (Leigh's mother's side) (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Ortenburger family (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Ortenburger, Arthur I. (father), genealogy, estate papers, 1898-1961 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Norman High School, graduation 1947 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Deep Springs Newsletters, 1968-1986 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Deep Springs College brochures (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Deep Springs College fundraising, 1986, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Deep Springs College reunion, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Deep Springs College fundraising, 1990-1991 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Telluride Newsletters, 1969-1981 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - University of Oklahoma, Sigma Alpha Epsilon (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Further education (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Health (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Running, Fun Run certificates 1975-1980 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Running, miscellaneous (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Running, 1976-1989 (Box 21, Folder 3-11)
  - Bicycling, 1983-1984 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Mountaineering clippings and articles (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Ortenburger, Leigh N., lists of climbs (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Ortenburger, Leigh N., list of Peru climbs (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Ortenburger, Leigh N., Christmas cards (mountain photos) (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Christmas cards, list of addresses, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Collected cartoons and humor (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Annapurna, American Women's Himalayan Expedition, clippings, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Alpine Club, songbook, history, photos (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Ortenburger, Carolyn D., Yale graduation, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous unfiled (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Ancient Civilizations of Mexico, notes (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Parks and Recreation, Bay Area, brochures, 1970s-1980s (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Skiing brochures, 1970s-1980s (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Dog equipment catalogs (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Ortenburger, Leigh N., housesitting instructions (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Rainier, Shasta, McKinley information (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Wine articles (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Wine miscellaneous (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Wine tasting (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Wine invoices (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Wine labels (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Citizen's band radio (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Cameras (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Photography, miscellaneous correspondence (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Tea catalogs (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous papers (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Mountain photography business (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Mountain clippings, obituaries (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - To do lists, 9/30/1991 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Ortenburger, Leigh N., obituary by Clinch, Nicholas, American Alpine Journal 1992, pp 288-291. (Box 23, Folder 15)
- Series 6: Employment at GTE Sylvania
  This series consists of material related to employment. After serving two years in the U.S. Army, Leigh spent his entire working career at GTE Sylvania, doing largely classified work related to radio communications. He continued to consult there after retirement.
  - Employment, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Retirement, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Company newsletters, 1978-1985 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Ortenburger, Leigh N., "Signal Coverage Redundancy," draft (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Consulting after retirement (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Consulting notes (Box 24, Folder 6-8)
  - Comite Consultatif International des Radiocommunications (CCIR) Interim Working Party, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - CCIR Interim Working Party, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Reprints re radio communications, etc. (Box 25, Folder 2-end)
  - Reprints re radio communications, etc. (Box 26, Folder 1-end)
  - Reprints re radio communications, etc. (Box 27, Folder 1-5)
- Series 7: Mountaineering Equipment and Food
  This series contains tent design and fabrics, notes on equipment, expedition equipment lists, lists of books and catalogs, and correspondence with the following: Ayres, Fred D.; Baker, Paul T.; Bauer, Eddie; Baxter, Alfred; Bell, George I.; Creswell, Alexander. E.; Cunnngham, Gerry A.; Dingman, David L.; DiPaolo, Mario; Edgington, Benjamin; Holubar, Alice; Houston, Charles S.; Irvin, Richard K.; Lamphere, R. M.; Lawrie, Robert; Matthews, W. V. Graham; Michael, David; Reis, Paul; Rosberg, O. A.; Steck, Allen; Stephenson, Jack, et al.
  - Tent fabric information (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Tent fabric correspondence (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Tent pole materials (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Two-man tent calculations (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Logan tent calculations (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Equipment making, sleeping bags, tents, parkas (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Equipment, miscellaneous (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Gerry Mountaineering Equipment Co., correspondence, 1952-1960 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Mountaineering equipment, correspondence, 1952-1958 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Expedition equipment lists (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Mountaineering equipment catalogs (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Expedition medicine, high altitude pulmonary edema (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Mountain Safety Research Newsletters, 1970-1978 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Expedition food lists (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Mountaineering books, catalogs, and correspondence (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Mountaineering, miscellaneous publications (Box 37, Folder 6-8)
- Series 8: Sierra Club
  This series contains minutes of the Sierra Club Mountaineering Committee, newsletters of the Loma Prieta Chapter, Rock Climbing Section, and includes mention of the following: Barnes, George; Brower, David R.; Brown, Richard; Clinch, Nicholas; Condon, Tom; Engs, William D.; Erb, Arkel; Fitschen, Joe; Gnagy, Rich; Hoyte, John M.; Irvin, Richard (Dick); King, Pat; Kingsley, Norman; Kruse, Dale; Kruse, Scott M.; Levine, Mike; McBride, Norman; McHale, Dan; McLean, Richard; Oetzel, George; Philpott, Robert; Powers, Jim; Reynolds, G. W.; Schlager, Walt; Secor, R. J.; Sherrick, Mike; Shinno, George; Siri, William E.; Steck, Allen; Sykes, Richard; Thomas, William H.; Thornton, John; Turney, Burt; Walcott, Francis J.; Wedberg, John; Wilts, Chuck., et al.
  - Sierra Club, miscellaneous (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Sierra Club Mountaineering Committee, minutes, 1962-1974 (Box 29, Folder 6-7)
  - Sierra Club, Loma Prieta Chapter, Rock Climbing Section newsletter, 1974-1976 (Box 29, Folder 8)
- Series 9: American Alpine Club
  This series contains the American Alpine Club News, 1951-1974, information about annual meetings, the work of various committees, the reception of the David A. Sowles Memorial Award, and correspondence with the following: Albinson, Corrine; Ames, Alcides; Angell, James; Armato, David N.; Baldwin, Neil; Beckey, Fred; Bedayn, Raffi; Bell, George I.; Benner, Gordon A.; Bernholdt, Brett; Bidwell, David D.; Blakeney, T. S.; Bleser, Warren; Blomberg, Greg; Bol, Thomas; Bolyard, Dudley W.; Bonney, Orrin H.; Brett, John F.; Briggs, William; Brill, Timothy J.; Brittson, Ted; Brown, Keith; Buhler, Carlos P.; Burgess, Adrian; Burgess, Alan; Burgess, Richard; Burleson, Todd,; Burton, Hal; Calegan, Nino; Carter, H. Adams; Cary, F. L.; Castle, Alfred L.; Chappman, Howard; Child, William S.; Christian, John; Clapp, Jeff; Corbet, Barry; Coveney, Lawrence G.; Craig, Robert W.; Cronk, C. P.; Crush, Charles C.; Cunningham, Gerry; De la Vega, Frank; Del Fium, Dorene; Donaldson, Greg; Dornan, David; Dube, Chris; Duller, Charles E.; Dyhrenfurth, Norman G.; Ebert, John; Eichorn, Jules M.; Evans, Charles; Everett, Jr., Boyd N.; Field, William O.; Firey, Joan; Fischer, Scott; Fleck, Helene; Fogarty, Mark W.; Fralick, John F.; Francis, Henry S., Jr.; Fritz, Dietrich; Frost, Thomas M.; Frush, Jim; Fuller, Carleton P.; Gillman, Bradley B.; Gilman, Bradley B.; Glidden, Jocelyn C. (Jock); Goodman, Donald J.; Goodwin, James; Graham, John D.; Gran, Art; Grissom, Kitty Calhoun; Hackett, William; Hall, John H.; Hall, Henry S., Jr.; Harrah, David; Harrington, Randal P.; Harrison, John C.; Hart, John L. J.; Hart, Stephen H.; Harvard, Andrew; Hauser, William E.; Hechtel, Richard; Hendricks, Sterling B.; Hennek, Dennis P.; Henriot, James F.; Herrigstad, Irving H. L.; Hoffman, Robert; Hofmann, Walther; Horn, Rick; Houchin, David; House, William P.; Houston, Charles S.; Hubbard, Donald; Hultgren, Herbert N.; Humphreys, John S.; Hunt, John; Ingalls, David B.; Irvin, Richard K.; Janis, Burt; Jerstad, Luther G.; Jervis, Steven; Johnson, Fred; Jones, Chris; Kauffman, Andrew J.; Kneebone, Terry; Knowlton, Elizabeth; Kopff, Gary J.; Kraus, Hans; Latz, Robert N.; Lippmann, Fritz; Liu, Rick; Logan, Lorens F.; Lombeck, Art C.; Lowe Michael; Lowe, George; Lowe, W. George; Matthews, W. V. Graham; McCarthy, James P.; McGowan, Richard; McKee, Margo; Measuroll, David W.; Mendenhall, Ruth D.; Menocal, Armando; Mention, David; Miller, E. Jack; Millikan, Rick; Mohling, Franz; Molenaar, Dee; Morales Arnao, Cesar; Mullen, Frances A.; Mutch, Thomas A. (Tim); Nabokov, Dmitri; Nettle, Dave; Nevison, Thomas O.; Newell, Daniel M.; Nilsson, Einar; Olmsted, John C.; Ortenburger, Leigh N.; Palmer, Roland; Patterson, Leif-Norman; Pfau, Paul; Porzak, Glenn E.; Pownall, Richard; Putnam, William L.; Read, William A. (Al); Reese, Rick; Reid, Christine L.; Reville, Kenneth; Roach, Robert; Roberts, James O. M.; Robbins, Royal; Rodman, Sayre; Romanowicz, Robert T.; Rupley, John A.; Sadler, Jack; Sainsbury, George R.; Schatz, Ruedi; Schoening, Pete; Shipton, Eric; Smith, Evan W.; Steck, Allen; Swenson, Steve; Swift, Robert L.; Terray, Marianne; Thorndike, Paul E.; Tilman, H. W.; Underhill, Miriam; Underhill, Robert L. M; Vadasz, Bela G.; Van Anda, Paul; Van Meter, Steve; Van Wagtendonk, Jan; Vargas Angeles, Eliseo; Wagstaff, Brock; Walton, Harold F.; Washburn, Jr., Bradford; Weissner, Fritz H.; Wendel., W. Hall, Jr.; Wheeler, Oliver; Whitehouse, Annie; Wilcox, Rick; Williamson, Jed; Wilson, Ted; Winchester, Leonard James; Wiseman, Paul W.; Wood, Walter A.; Woolsey, Elizabeth D.; Yardley, Nick; Yeary, Carl A.; Zimmermann, T. C. Price, et al.
  - American Alpine Club News, 1951-1974 (Box 30, Folder 1-3)
  - American Alpine Club (AAC) treasurer's reports, 1958-1976 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - AAC correspondence, 1951-1967 (Box 30, Folder 5-8)
  - AAC annual meeting, planning, Berkeley, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - AAC correspondence, 1968-1980 (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
  - AAC annual meetings, 1974-1983 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - AAC annual meeting, planning, Berkeley, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Ortenburger, Leigh N., received the David A. Sowles Memorial Award from the AAC for bravery in assisting others in distress, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 5)